<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Markdown | Memento Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://mementodb.github.com/categories/markdown/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mementodb.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-17T12:50:01+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://mementodb.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Memento]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inroducing Memento]]></title>
    <link href="http://mementodb.github.com/2012/11/08/inroducing-memento/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-08T12:23:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mementodb.github.com/2012/11/08/inroducing-memento</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is a wonderful online bookmarking application that allows you to save any web page that you like. We go beyond bookmarking and also archive the full-text of the page that you bookmark. You can think of memento as your personal inbox with all that you like on the web. <a href="http://www.mementodb.com/signup">Signup now for your free account</a>. It's quick and easy.</p>

<h2>What are mementos?</h2>

<p>Mementos are anything that you save using this application. You can think of a memento as a copy of the entire web page bookmarked and archived into your personal account for you to <strong>"use"</strong> later. When we say <strong>"use"</strong> we really mean you should be able to read, edit or print the mementos. For creating mementos we convert web pages that you want to collect into a Markdown, an awesome text format, that any one can edit without understanding the techonolgies of the web (HTML, CSS, and Javascript).</p>

<h2>Why Use Memento?</h2>

<p>Web is constantly changing, pages that you bookmark today may vanish tomorrow. But what if you found something on web that you want to keep as a personal memento. With Memento you can <strong>Save</strong>, <strong>Collect</strong> and <strong>Use</strong> your web.</p>

<p>Archived web page is not a dumb read only copy of the original page. It's an agile copy in <a href="">Markdwon</a> format. Markdown is the simple and best format out there that anyone can edit. We also provide ability to highlight, annotate, collaborate and share with your friends. For</p>

<h2>Why should use Memento?</h2>

<p>You should use memento</p>

<ol>
<li>If you never want to loose any page on the web to 404 error.</li>
<li>It's perfect for collaborating with your friends and colleague for sharing the research and collaborating .</li>
<li>If you want to organize everything you are bookmarking painlessly.</li>
<li>If you want to keep everything private like your email inbox but with the ability to share with friends.</li>
<li>Its free, awesome, and the best online bookmarking service.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Why we use Markdown?</h2>

<h2>How it Works?</h2>

<p>Memento provides a bookmarklet that converts the web page you want to keep into Markdown and saves it to your account.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Memento Features</h2>

<p>Memento is designed for usability and following are some of its features</p>

<ul>
<li>Simple and amazingly Fast.</li>
<li>Convert and Save any page as Memento.</li>
<li>Takes new Notes or edit your saved mementos.</li>
<li>Organize saved mementos using Tags.</li>
<li>Distraction free Reading environment.</li>
<li>Best Writing experience with Markdown.</li>
<li>Saved mementos are Printer friendly.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Memento Quicklook</h2>

<h3>List of mementos saved in your personal account</h3>

<p><img src="/images/hero-shot1.png" title="[title text [alt text]]" ></p>

<h3>Saving mementos using bookmarklet</h3>

<p><img src="/images/hero-shot2.png" title="[title text [alt text]]" ></p>

<h3>Saving mementos using bookmarklet (saved copy of page)</h3>

<p><img src="/images/hero-shot3.png" title="[title text [alt text]]" ></p>

<h2>Feedback, Ideas or Suggestions</h2>

<p>If you have any ideas, feedback, or suggestions for improving Memento then please email me at hgilani[at]mementodb[dot]com</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
